Well.
글쎄요
Fantastic.
환상적이에요
It's coming up to the end of the week, and that means it's coming up to a challenge for you again,
이번 주말이면 끝나요 다시 도전이 기다리고 있다는 뜻이죠 방금 제가 여러분께
even though I've just given you a challenge to build a Gradio user interface for for what we just saw.
그래디오 사용자 인터페이스를 구축하라고 과제를 드렸는데도요
But that's an easy challenge.
하지만 쉬운 도전이죠
You can do that.
할 수 있어요
No problem.
별말씀을요
This you need a harder challenge.
더 어려운 과제가 필요해요
At the end of the week, it's time for a harder challenge.
이번 주 후반에는 더 어려운 과제가 기다리고 있죠
So the end of week challenge is to build an important business application that we will, in fact,
마지막 챌린지는 중요한 비즈니스 응용 프로그램을 만드는 겁니다 나중에 이 과정을 통해
use later in the course.
사용할 거죠
Although yeah, you you won't need to to you won't need to have built it for that because because I'll
하지만 그걸 위해 만들 필요는 없어요 제가 만들 거니까요
But it's really helpful if you've done it.
하지만 해 본 사람이라면 정말 도움이 되죠
And this is something that you'll be able to use no matter in any business.
어떤 사업에서든 사용할 수 있는 거죠
This, this, this tool will apply to every business vertical and can be useful to you, I guarantee
이 도구는 모든 비즈니스에 적용될 겁니다 여러분께 유용할 거예요 제가 보장하죠
And this is what it is.
이게 그 결과예요
Create your own tool that generates synthetic testing data a test data generator, open source model.
합성 테스트 데이터를 생성하는 자신만의 도구를 만드세요 테스트 데이터 생성기 오픈 소스 모델이요
This is something that is so valuable.
정말 귀한 거예요
Generating data sets is something that you need for many different purposes.
데이터 세트 생성에는 여러 가지 목적이 필요해요
And I want to give you a very, um, wide remit to decide how you want to go about doing this, but
저는 여러분이 어떻게 하고 싶은지 결정할 수 있는 아주 폭넓은 권한을 드리고 싶습니다. 하지만 제가
I'm looking for something where you can describe a kind of data set you want, and maybe it's descriptions
원하는 것은 여러분이 원하는 데이터 세트를 묘사할 수 있는 것입니다. 제품에 대한
of products, maybe it's descriptions of, uh, um, uh, job postings, whatever it is you want to
설명일 수도 있고, 어 구인 공고일 수도 있습니다. 여러분의 제품이 무엇인지, 여러분이 작업하고
be able to, to tell your product what it is, what kind of data that you're working with and let it
있는 데이터는 어떤 종류인지, 그리고 다양한 출력과 다양한 테스트 세트를 꿈꿀
dream up, uh, diverse outputs, diverse test set that you'll be able to use when experimenting with
수 있도록 하는 것입니다. 이로써 앞으로 여러분의 비즈니스 영역에서 실험할 때 사용할 수 있을 수 있을 거예요.
So this synthetic data generator is going to be a valuable tool for yourself, for me and for for this,
이 합성 데이터 발생기는 여러분과 저, 그리고 이걸 위해 귀중한 도구가 될 겁니다 이 과정과
both for this course and for future business problems you tackle.
미래의 사업 문제에 있어서요
So it's worth investing some time in, and it's worth giving it a gradio UI while you're doing it.
시간을 투자할 가치가 있고 그러데이션 UI를 적용할 가치가 있어요
And that's going to be the super easy part.
아주 쉬운 부분이에요
So I have a shot at that.
그래서 저도 도전해 보려고요
It will apply to your business area no matter what you do.
뭘 하든 비즈니스 영역에 적용되죠
It's going to be useful and you're going to really enjoy it.
유용하고 정말 즐기실 수 있어요
And then that would then complete week three, wrapping up your third week of your journey towards being
그러면 3주 차를 마무리합니다 여정의 3주 차를 마무리하면 능숙한 LM 엔지니어가
a proficient LM engineer.
되는 거죠
You can already, of course, code confidently with frontier models.
물론 개척 시대 모델로 이미 코드를 만들 수 있죠
You must be sick of me saying that now because you're that good.
이제 와서 이런 말 하는 거 지겹죠?
You can build an AI assistant.
인공지능 보조를 만들 수 있어요
You can have it be multimodal, you can have it use tools.
멀티모덜이 될 수도 있고 도구를 사용할 수도 있죠
You can have it be consist of multiple smaller agents that carry out specialist tasks.
여러 명의 작은 요원들로 구성해 전문 임무를 수행할 수도 있죠
And of course, at this point you can create an LM solution that combines calls to frontier models.
물론 이 시점에서 여러분은 프런티어 모델에 호출하는 LM 솔루션을 만들 수 있죠
And it can call open source models.
오픈 소스 모델을 호출할 수 있어요
And you can use the pipeline API, using it to to carry out a large variety of common inference tasks.
파이프라인 API를 사용할 수 있습니다 일반 추론 작업을 수행하기 위해 다양하게 사용하죠
And you can also use the lower level hugging face APIs, the Tokenizers, and the models for inference
하위 레벨의 얼굴 포옹 API를 사용할 수도 있습니다 토큰라이저와 추론 작업을 위한
tasks.
모델을요
So congratulations once again, you should be very proud next week.
다시 한번 축하드려요 다음 주에는 자랑스러워하세요
Next week we change topics.
다음 주엔 화제를 바꾸죠
There's a thorny question.
가시가 돋친 질문이네요
It's a question I get asked all the time.
Get it, get it get it get it
It's something which is, uh, where there's actually a lot of great resources to help.
실제로 도움이 될 만한 훌륭한 자원이 많은 곳이죠
It's about how do you pick the right model for the for a given task that you have to work on.
주어진 작업에 맞는 모델을 어떻게 고르느냐가 관건이죠
There are so many models, there are so many options.
모델도 많고 옵션도 많아요
There's for staff.
직원용이에요
There's there's do you go closed source or open source?
비공개 소스인가요 오픈 소스인가요?
But then whichever path you take, there are so many possibilities.
하지만 어떤 길을 택하든 가능성은 무궁무진해요
And how do you navigate through this to decide which one is right for a particular problem.
특정 문제에 어떤 게 적절한지 어떻게 탐색해야 할까요?
And that is the key.
그게 핵심이에요
It depends on the problem.
어떤 문제냐에 따라 다르죠
Different models will be appropriate for different problems.
다른 문제에는 다른 모델이 적합하죠
I'm going to show you how to figure that out.
어떻게 하는지 보여드릴게요
We're going to compare LMS.
LMS를 비교할 거예요
We're going to use leaderboards.
리더보드를 사용할 거예요
We're going to use arenas.
아레나에서 할 거예요
And we're going to do some some work with arenas ourselves.
우리도 아레나에서 작업 좀 하려고요
And that's going to be fun.
재미있을 거예요
And then as our practical work, we're going to to go a different direction than we've gone in the past,
실제 업무로서 과거와는 다른 방향으로 갈 겁니다 아주 간략하게
except we did it very briefly once, but we're going to be looking at code generation when we're using
한 번 했지만요 프론티어 모델과 오픈 소스 모델을 이용해
frontier models and open source models to be generating code and tackling some code generation problems.
코드 생성 문제를 해결하면서 코드 생성을 살펴볼 거예요
So that will be a new, interesting perspective for you.
새롭고 흥미로운 관점이 될 거예요
So I'm really excited about next week, and I'm so, so impressed by how much progress you've made already
다음 주가 정말 기대돼요 여러분이 벌써 이렇게 많이 발전하고
and how many skills that you've already acquired.
많은 기술을 습득한 게 정말 인상적이에요
And I will see you for week four for picking the right LLM.
적절한 LLM을 선택해서 4주 차에 만나요